<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Abdullah Khabir</title>
        <link>https://abdullah.today/</link>
        <description>An InfoSec related Blog</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>abdullah@abdullah.today (Abdullah Khabir)</managingEditor>
            <webMaster>abdullah@abdullah.today (Abdullah Khabir)</webMaster><copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2022 18:07:52 &#43;0500</lastBuildDate>
            <atom:link href="https://abdullah.today/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <item>
    <title>Trigger a Jenkins Build on Every Code Push Event</title>
    <link>https://abdullah.today/trigger-a-jenkins-build-on-every-code-push-event/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2022 18:07:52 &#43;0500</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://abdullah.today/trigger-a-jenkins-build-on-every-code-push-event/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Configure GitHub project Go to your GitHub repository settings and click on Webhooks. Click on add a webhook.
In payload URL, add your jenkins installation URL + &lsquo;/github-webhook/&rsquo;. For example if my jenkins is running at https://jenkins.example.com:8080, I&rsquo;ll add https://jenkins.example.com:8080/github-webhook/. Disable SSL verification. Select send me everything or you can select only push events. and lastly check the box which says Active.
Configure Jenkins project Go to your jenkins project configuration.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Installing MPD on CentOS7</title>
    <link>https://abdullah.today/install-mpd-on-centos7/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jun 2022 01:32:54 &#43;0500</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://abdullah.today/install-mpd-on-centos7/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/images/mpd.jpeg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>Why CentOS7? Sometimes in production you have to use CentOS7 even if it has lost its life. Or you might be working with vagrant and only OS you have available is CentOS7.
Installing packages from official repositories CentOS7 has very limited packages available in official repositories. So you have to install epel-release and nux-dextop packages to extend your packages list.
Install epel-release By default, epel-release isn&rsquo;t installed. So first step you have to install epel-release.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Persistent Backdoor in Linux Environment</title>
    <link>https://abdullah.today/persistent-backdoor-in-linux-environment/</link>
    <pubDate>Thu, 18 Feb 2021 14:53:36 &#43;0500</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://abdullah.today/persistent-backdoor-in-linux-environment/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[So you have hacked a linux box. Next step should be leave a persistent backdoor so in case, it is rebooted, you have to repeat all those steps again and again.
There are multiple methods available to create a persistent backdoor. Today I&rsquo;m going to explain how you can create a backdoor in webservers.
Tools needed socat weevely some common sense Installing Tools weevely Install weevely if you don&rsquo;t have it.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Things to Do After New OpenBSD Install</title>
    <link>https://abdullah.today/things-to-do-after-new-openbsd-install/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2021 18:52:24 &#43;0500</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://abdullah.today/things-to-do-after-new-openbsd-install/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[So you have installed OpenBSD as main OS. Most of the things will work out of the box. But still you have to configure some things.
Lock screen on suspend/hibernate/resume Login as root and create /etc/apm directory if it isn&rsquo;t there already.
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 mkdir /etc/apm echo &#34;pkill -USR1 xidle&#34; &gt; /etc/apm/suspend echo &#34;pkill -USR1 xidle&#34; &gt; /etc/apm/resume echo &#34;pkill -USR1 xidle&#34; &gt; /etc/apm/hibernate chmod +x /etc/apm/suspend chmod +x /etc/apm/hibernate chmod +x /etc/apm/resume On lid closure, machines mostly get suspended.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>OpenBSD Encrypted Install</title>
    <link>https://abdullah.today/openbsd-encrypted-install/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 09 Feb 2021 20:12:36 &#43;0500</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://abdullah.today/openbsd-encrypted-install/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[So this is how you can have a fully encrypted OpenBSD installation.
Getting OpenBSD Go to OpenBSD website and download the .img file for your hardware.
Creating install media If you are on some linux or mac, you can use dd command to burn it to USB drive.
Suppose your USB drive is appearing as /dev/sdb in lsblk&rsquo;s output:
1 dd if=install.img of=/dev/sdb bs=1M Boot from install media Plug the new install media and reboot the system.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>OpenBSD Dedicated Dotfiles</title>
    <link>https://abdullah.today/openbsd-dedicated-dotfiles/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 08 Feb 2021 11:37:18 &#43;0500</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://abdullah.today/openbsd-dedicated-dotfiles/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/images/think-securely.jpeg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>OpenBSD as new OS I keep my dotfiles on Github/Gitlab. I had to configure many things so I started a dedicated repository.
New Dotfiles I created a new directory dot in my home dir. And cherry picked some of my old dots. I have pushed my new dot directory to Git[hub,lab] as [Awan,Abdullah]/dot respectively.
Old Linux dotfiles Linux users still can find my dotfiles on Github and Gitlab.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Honda125 2021</title>
    <link>https://abdullah.today/honda125-2021/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2021 19:41:58 &#43;0500</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://abdullah.today/honda125-2021/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/images/bike8.jpg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>So here is new bike for 2021. Here are some pictures. I hope you&rsquo;ll like them&hellip;
Honda 125 Honda 125 Honda 125 Honda 125 Honda 125 Honda 125 Honda 125 Honda 125 Honda 125 Honda 125 Honda 125 ]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Linux Filesystem Directory Structure</title>
    <link>https://abdullah.today/linux-filesystem-directory-structure/</link>
    <pubDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2020 14:24:49 &#43;0500</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://abdullah.today/linux-filesystem-directory-structure/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Unlike other operating systems, in linux everything starts from /. This is called root directory.
You can use cd command to navigate in filesystem. If you&rsquo;re inside some directory and you want to know where you&rsquo;re inside the directory tree, just type pwd and it will show you the current working directory. pwd stands for print working directory.
cd command needs some arguments if you want to visit some other directory.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Send Mail Using Gmail using Command Line</title>
    <link>https://abdullah.today/send-mail-using-gmail-from-terminal/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 29 Nov 2020 07:32:13 &#43;0500</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://abdullah.today/send-mail-using-gmail-from-terminal/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Yeah, you can send mail from your gmail account using command line.
Requirements You have two options here.
Gmail account settings Either enable less secure apps in your Google account or Generate an app password.
Tools being used For Arch Linux:
1 $ sudo pacman -S msmtp For Debian, Ubuntu and other Debian derived distributions:
1 $ sudo apt install -y msmtp For Fedora, CentOS, Redhat etc:
1 $ sudo dnf install msmtp Encrypt password Using gpg, we are going to encrypt our password.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>SSH Passwordless Authentication</title>
    <link>https://abdullah.today/ssh-passwordless-authentication/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 13:45:06 &#43;0500</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://abdullah.today/ssh-passwordless-authentication/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[SSH login without password? Yeah you heard it right. Today I&rsquo;m going to teach you how you can enable passwordless authentication in ssh.
You can login to your linux servers without password. How? Keep reading&hellip;
Edit the SSH main configuration file.
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 $ sudo vi /etc/ssh/sshd_config ... PubkeyAuthentication yes ... Edit this line. If you see no, change it to yes. If this line is commented out, uncomment it.]]></description>
</item></channel>
</rss>
