<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>github on Abdullah</title>
    <link>https://abdullah.today/tags/github/</link>
    <description>Recent content in github on Abdullah</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://abdullah.today/tags/github/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>How to include a screenshot in Github README</title>
      <link>https://abdullah.today/github-readme/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abdullah.today/github-readme/</guid>
      <description>A picture is worth 1000 words. Working with github repos, sometimes you want to include a screenshot in your repos. Today I&amp;rsquo;ll help you getting this done in one step.
Go to your repo page and click on issues.
Click new issue
Take a screenshot you wanna add and paste it there using Control + V or whatever you like.
   ;(adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({})  You will get a link once the screenshot is uploaded.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create/paste snippets from Terminal</title>
      <link>https://abdullah.today/gists/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abdullah.today/gists/</guid>
      <description>What&amp;rsquo;s snippet/gist? gist is a piece of code or maybe some important text shared on Github or Gitlab. It&amp;rsquo;s actually a git repository so you can clone it, work on it locally and push changes.
Share gists from Terminal There are multiple programs available in many distributions for this purpose. You just have to find it. On Arch Linux, you can install gist.
Here is how it works in terminal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to contribute to open source project</title>
      <link>https://abdullah.today/contribution-with-git/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abdullah.today/contribution-with-git/</guid>
      <description>So you want to contribute to some open source project which is hosted on git[hub,lab] or some other git website. Here is all you want to do.
Fork the repository Create a personal fork. On github, visit the project repository and hit fork. It will fork the project in your personal account.
Clone it Clone it in your local machine so you can work on it. Remember you are cloning the fork, and not the original project.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>