<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>git - Tag - Abdullah Khabir</title>
        <link>https://abdullah.today/tags/git/</link>
        <description>git - Tag - Abdullah Khabir</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>abdullah@abdullah.today (Abdullah Khabir)</managingEditor>
            <webMaster>abdullah@abdullah.today (Abdullah Khabir)</webMaster><copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2022 18:07:52 &#43;0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://abdullah.today/tags/git/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
    <title>Trigger a Jenkins Build on Every Code Push Event</title>
    <link>https://abdullah.today/trigger-a-jenkins-build-on-every-code-push-event/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2022 18:07:52 &#43;0500</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://abdullah.today/trigger-a-jenkins-build-on-every-code-push-event/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Configure GitHub project Go to your GitHub repository settings and click on Webhooks. Click on add a webhook.
In payload URL, add your jenkins installation URL + &lsquo;/github-webhook/&rsquo;. For example if my jenkins is running at https://jenkins.example.com:8080, I&rsquo;ll add https://jenkins.example.com:8080/github-webhook/. Disable SSL verification. Select send me everything or you can select only push events. and lastly check the box which says Active.
Configure Jenkins project Go to your jenkins project configuration.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Git Initial Setup</title>
    <link>https://abdullah.today/configure-git/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jul 2020 18:58:13 &#43;0500</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://abdullah.today/configure-git/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/images/git.jpeg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>How to configure Git Git is a version control system by Linus Torvalds, same person who wrote linux kernel.
Installation In Archlinux, you can install git by:
1 $ sudo pacman -S git In Debian and derived distributions:
1 $ sudo apt install -y git Configuration You have to tell git about the author who committed changes so lets do it.
Name and Email Tell git about your name and email:]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>git Cherry Pick</title>
    <link>https://abdullah.today/cherry-pick/</link>
    <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jun 2020 14:25:08 &#43;0500</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://abdullah.today/cherry-pick/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Git cherry-picking Aah picking cherries! â¤ï¸
I&rsquo;m using git since I started using linux. Cherry-pick is one of those commands I do alot with git. Right now I&rsquo;m preparing a new cherry and will pick it later. ðŸ˜‰
What&rsquo;s cherry-pick? According to man(1) git-cherry-pick:
1 2 3 4 Given one or more existing commits, apply the change each one introduces, recording a new commit for each. This requires your working tree to be clean (no modifications from the HEAD commit).]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>How to manage a website using git</title>
    <link>https://abdullah.today/site-as-git-repo/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 10 May 2020 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://abdullah.today/site-as-git-repo/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Git is another awesome tool developed and maintained by Linus Torvalds who wrote linux kernel. In this post I&rsquo;ll explain how can we use it for our site maintenance. I have a vps on which my site is hosted along with a mail server, git server and a web server too. But I&rsquo;m sure this guide can be used with shared hosting accounts with some modifications.
Install git. Once installed, as root user, create git user and add it to www-data group.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>How to contribute to open source project</title>
    <link>https://abdullah.today/contribution-with-git/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2020 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://abdullah.today/contribution-with-git/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[So you want to contribute to some open source project which is hosted on git[hub,lab] or some other git website. Here is all you want to do.
Fork the repository Create a personal fork. On github, visit the project repository and hit fork. It will fork the project in your personal account.
Clone it Clone it in your local machine so you can work on it. Remember you are cloning the fork, and not the original project.]]></description>
</item></channel>
</rss>
