<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>All Posts - Abdullah Khabir</title>
        <link>https://abdullah.today/posts/</link>
        <description>All Posts | Abdullah Khabir</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>abdullah@abdullah.today (Abdullah Khabir)</managingEditor>
            <webMaster>abdullah@abdullah.today (Abdullah Khabir)</webMaster><copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Feb 2021 11:37:18 &#43;0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://abdullah.today/posts/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
    <title>Openbsd Dedicated Dotfiles</title>
    <link>https://abdullah.today/openbsd-dedicated-dotfiles/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 08 Feb 2021 11:37:18 &#43;0500</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://abdullah.today/openbsd-dedicated-dotfiles/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/images/think-securely.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>OpenBSD as new OS So I started using OpenBSD in start of 2021. My blog readers know I keep my dotfiles on Github/Gitlab. Most of the programs I have been using in past were okay with this change. But I had to configure many things.
New Dotfiles I created a new directory dot in my home dir. And cherry picked some of my old dots. But still that wasn&rsquo;t enough. It took me 2 months to figure things out as per my liking.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Honda125 2021</title>
    <link>https://abdullah.today/honda125-2021/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2021 19:41:58 &#43;0500</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://abdullah.today/honda125-2021/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/images/bike8.jpg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>So here is new bike for 2021. Here are some pictures. I hope you&rsquo;ll like them&hellip;
Honda 125" Honda 125  Honda 125" Honda 125  Honda 125" Honda 125  Honda 125" Honda 125  Honda 125" Honda 125  Honda 125" Honda 125  Honda 125" Honda 125  Honda 125" Honda 125  Honda 125" Honda 125  Honda 125" Honda 125  Honda 125" Honda 125]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Linux Filesystem Directory Structure</title>
    <link>https://abdullah.today/linux-filesystem-directory-structure/</link>
    <pubDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2020 14:24:49 &#43;0500</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://abdullah.today/linux-filesystem-directory-structure/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Unlike other operating systems, in linux everything starts from /. This is called root directory.
You can use cd command to navigate in filesystem. If you&rsquo;re inside some directory and you want to know where you&rsquo;re inside the directory tree, just type pwd and it will show you the current working directory. pwd stands for print working directory.
cd command needs some arguments if you want to visit some other directory.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Send Mail Using Gmail using Command Line</title>
    <link>https://abdullah.today/send-mail-using-gmail-from-terminal/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 29 Nov 2020 07:32:13 &#43;0500</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://abdullah.today/send-mail-using-gmail-from-terminal/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Yeah, you can send mail from your gmail account using command line.
Requirements You have two options here.
Gmail account settings Either enable less secure apps in your Google account or Generate an app password.
Tools being used For Arch Linux:
1  $ sudo pacman -S msmtp   For Debian, Ubuntu and other Debian derived distributions:
1  $ sudo apt install -y msmtp   For Fedora, CentOS, Redhat etc:]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>SSH Passwordless Authentication</title>
    <link>https://abdullah.today/ssh-passwordless-authentication/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 13:45:06 &#43;0500</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://abdullah.today/ssh-passwordless-authentication/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[SSH login without password? Yeah you heard it right. Today I&rsquo;m going to teach you how you can enable passwordless authentication in ssh.
You can login to your linux servers without password. How? Keep reading&hellip;
Edit the SSH main configuration file.
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10  $ sudo vi /etc/ssh/sshd_config ... PubkeyAuthentication yes ...   Edit this line. If you see no, change it to yes.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>How to Share Android Screen</title>
    <link>https://abdullah.today/how-to-share-android-screen/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2020 13:21:18 &#43;0500</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://abdullah.today/how-to-share-android-screen/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[There are times you want to share your android phone&rsquo;s screen with your Linux/Windows desktop. Like if you have got broken screen or for some purpose.
So this post may help you.
Requirements  Android phone ADB installed  In Arch Linux, you can install ADB with:
1 2 3  $ sudo pacman -S android-tools   There is a program which is used to screen sharing. You can install it using AUR in Arch Linux, use apt if you are using Ubuntu/Debian.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Kalilinux Persistence</title>
    <link>https://abdullah.today/kalilinux-persistence/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2020 17:22:11 &#43;0500</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://abdullah.today/kalilinux-persistence/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Getting Kalilinux image Go to Downloads and download latest live image. Make sure you don&rsquo;t download the installer image.
Make USB bootable Use dd to write the kali image to USB.
In linux environment:
1  # dd if=kali-linux-xxxx.x-live-amd64.iso of=/dev/sdX status=progress bs=4M   Replace kali-linux-xxxx.x-live-amd64.iso with downloaded iso iamge path and /dev/sdX with path of your USB device. You can find USB path by running lsblk in terminal. Make sure you don&rsquo;t select the existing linux installation drive.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Git Initial Setup</title>
    <link>https://abdullah.today/configure-git/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jul 2020 18:58:13 &#43;0500</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://abdullah.today/configure-git/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[How to configure Git Git is a version control system by Linus Torvalds, same person who wrote linux kernel.
Installation In Archlinux, you can install git by:
1  $ sudo pacman -S git   In Debian and derived distributions:
1  $ sudo apt install -y git   Configuration You have to tell git about the author who committed changes so lets do it.
Name and Email Tell git about your name and email:]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>How to set FQDN in Linux</title>
    <link>https://abdullah.today/fqdn/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2020 13:26:14 &#43;0500</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://abdullah.today/fqdn/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[What is FQDN? FQDN stands for Fully Qualified Domain Name. It&rsquo;s complete domain name for a computer or host on the internet. FQDN is made of two things: hostname and domain name.
Let me give you an example for demonstration.
FQDN for my mail server is myemailserver.abdullah.today.
The hostname is myemailserver. The domain is abdullah.today.
Requirements You will need:
 IP Address Hostname FQDN  Edit hosts file Edit the /etc/hosts file and append this like this.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>TMUX</title>
    <link>https://abdullah.today/tmux/</link>
    <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jun 2020 18:13:35 &#43;0500</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://abdullah.today/tmux/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[TMUX tmux is a terminal multiplexer. You can run programs inside a tmux session, detach session and continue running programs in background, reattach later.
Installation tmux is available in all linux distributions. You can install it using your distribution&rsquo;s package manager. In Arch Linux:
1  $ sudo pacman -S tmux   Start You can start tmux by invoking tmux command inside your terminal.
Keybindings The default modifier key is Ctrl + b followed by a key.]]></description>
</item></channel>
</rss>
